[
    {
        "question": "How to select all the fields available in the table?",
        "choices": ["SELECT * FROM table_name;", "SELECT ALL FROM table_name;", "SELECT FROM table_name;", "SELECT # FROM table_name;"],
        "type": "radio",
        "correctAnswer": "SELECT * FROM table_name;"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which word is used to filter records?",
        "choices": ["WHERE", "IF", "CONDITION", "FROM"],
        "type": "radio",
        "correctAnswer": "WHERE"
    },
    {
        "question": "Is this statement valid?",
        "description": "SELECT LastName, FirstName, Address FROM Persons WHERE Address IS NULL;",
        "choices": ["yes", "no"],
        "type": "radio",
        "correctAnswer": "yes"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does RDBMS stand for?",
        "choices": ["Relational Database Management System", "Relational Database Microsoft System", "Relational Database MySQL", "Relational Database MongoDB System"],
        "type": "radio",
        "correctAnswer": "Relational Database Management System"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does SQL stand for?",
        "choices": ["Structured Query Language", "Structured Query List", "System Query Language"],
        "type": "radio",
        "correctAnswer": "Structured Query Language"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does DDL stand for?",
        "choices": ["Data Definition Language", "Data Destruction Language", "Domain Definition Language"],
        "type": "radio",
        "correctAnswer": "Data Definition Language"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does DML stand for?",
        "choices": ["Data Manipulation Language", "Data Manifestation Language", "Domain Manipulation Language"],
        "type": "radio",
        "correctAnswer": "Data Manipulation Language"
    },
    {
        "question": "What can SQL do?",
        "choices": ["It can insert records in a database", "It can create views in a database", "It can create new databases", "It can be executed inside HTML document"],
        "type": "select",
        "correctAnswer": ["It can insert records in a database", "It can create views in a database", "It can create new databases"]
    },
    {
        "question": "The OR operator displays a record if ANY conditions listed are true. The AND operator displays a record if ALL of the conditions listed are true.",
        "choices": ["true", "false"],
        "type": "radio",
        "correctAnswer": "true"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which SQL keyword is used to sort the result-set?",
        "choices": ["ORDER BY", "SORT BY", "SORT", "ORDER"],
        "type": "radio",
        "correctAnswer": "ORDER BY"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which operator is used to select values within a range?",
        "type": "input",
        "correctAnswer": "BETWEEN"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which operator is used in a WHERE clause to search for a specified pattern in a column?",
        "type": "input",
        "correctAnswer": "LIKE"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which function returns the number of rows that matches a specified criteria?",
        "type": "input",
        "correctAnswer": "COUNT"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which operator displays a record if all the conditions separated by it is TRUE?",
        "choices": ["AND", "&&", "OR", "||"],
        "type": "radio",
        "correctAnswer": "AND"
    },
    {
        "question": "Write a query to select all columns from the city table",
        "type": "input",
        "correctAnswer": "SELECT * FROM city;"
    },
    {
        "question": "Write a query to delete the city table from a database.",
        "type": "input",
        "correctAnswer": "DROP TABLE city;"
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose correct MySQL text data types.",
        "choices": ["LONGTEXT", "BLOB", "SMALLTEXT", "MIDDLEBLOB"],
        "type": "select",
        "correctAnswer": ["LONGTEXT", "BLOB"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose correct MySQL number data types.",
        "choices": ["TINYINT", "BIGINT", "MIDDLEINT", "LONG"],
        "type": "select",
        "correctAnswer": ["TINYINT", "BIGINT"]
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming a database has the following table. Choose valid INSERT statements.",
        "description": "CREATE TABLE STUDENTS (\n  ID INTEGER PRIMARY KEY,\n  FIRST_NAME VARCHAR(50) NOT NULL,\n  LAST_NAME VARCHAR(50) NOT NULL,\n  ADDRESS VARCHAR(100)\n)",
        "choices": ["INSERT INTO students VALUES (3, 'John', 'Doe', NULL);", "insert into students(id, first_name, last_name) values (1, 'Dan', 'Hall');", "INSERT INTO students(id, first_name) VALUES (2, 'Jack');", "INSERT INTO students VALUES (4, NULL, 'Till', NULL);"],
        "type": "radio",
        "correctAnswer": ["INSERT INTO students VALUES (3, 'John', 'Doe', NULL);",]
    }
]
